

# VISHNU VARDHAN

| Mobile: +91-9994798037 | | E-Mail: vardhan.vishnu@outlook.com\_|Website: www.vishnuvardhan.net| | LinkedIn - www.linkedin.com/in/vardhanvishnu | YouTube - http://tiny.cc/vishnuvardhan |

| Public Speaking | Professional Training & Coaching | Education Management | | Digital Monetization Strategy | CRM | | Anchoring | Marketing | Empathetic Leadership |

With over 5 years of experience in training and management currently in search of a role in Education Management, Leadership, Corporate Training, Strategy, Training & Development, Teaching and Public Speaking

Strategic, innovative, and eloquent speaker with a verifiable record of over 5 years in several facets of the corporate world; a compelling and an inspiring oration style. Strongly believes in the quote "When we were born we cried and the people around us smiled. Live life so that when you die you are smiling and the people around you are crying", similarly will make sure my tenure in the organization will have a positive and productive impact.

AS A PASSIONATE PUBLIC SPEAKER, TRAINING IN THIS AREA CAME NATURALLY TO ME. I STRONGLY DESIRE TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE AND EMPOWER YOUNG PROFESSIONALS AND STUDENTS

## ~ Value Proposition ~

- A Dale Carnegie Certified Trainer conducted trainings for over 25,000 SME Entrepreneurs and various behavioural trainings
  for the team members. Hosted Quiz Shows, anchored various national level events and conducted training sessions which had
  received over 75,000 views in YouTube Channel.
- Invigorating speaker with an empathetic leadership style, apt in creating a strong business-minded team and in motivating staff to peak performance to delivers results.
- Organisation builder holding the merit of working in start-up environment and instrumental in setting up go-to-market model by
  establishing the unit from scratch including building team, recruitment, sales planning, CRM, monetization planning, Marketing
  (BTL) and Product Management as Head Sales & Monetization Strategy.
- Highly ethical and an articulate speaker with excellent sales, marketing, team building, and training skills; embraces and thrives in challenging environment. Success in interacting easily with people of diverse backgrounds and cultures (Singaporeans, Africans and Indians).

#### **Employment History**

#### **Head - Sales & Monetization Strategy** ▶ VConnect Global Services Ltd.

Apr 2011 - Aug 2014

VConnect is a part of Tolaram Corporation Pte Ltd, which is headquartered in Singapore. Over 1 million businesses are listed on its website; recently the company was mentioned in Forbes as one of the Hottest Tech Start-ups in Africa

# Career Progression with Significant Highlights

# As Head - Sales & Monetization Strategy (Sep 2012- Aug 2014)

- Ensured the skill enhancement of the existing as well as the new hired employees by engaging in analysing the workforce plan, identifying skills, competency requirements and critical skill gaps across the organization followed by **developing various training programs** as per the organizational/business requirements.
- Headed monetization of the largest local search engine in Africa with key accountability of forecasting sales targets & executing them in given time frame by organisational planning and training the team.
- Evolved new avenues & driving revenue growth and proactively conducted opportunity analysis by keeping abreast of market trends/ competitor moves to achieve market-share metrics.
- Conducted various trainings on Sales Process, Customer Relation Management, Conflict Management, Stress Management, Employee Motivation, Marketing and Leadership.

#### Significant Highlights:

- Instrumental in conceptualising the "flash" idea (Other name of missed call in Africa) while serving as an integral part of the "Flash Product Team" www.flash.ng is a mobile marketing and analytics platform with simple missed calls.
- Evolved new revenue stream "flash" an entirely new mobile marketing solution with missed calls" which created a strong revenue pipeline with leading clients like P&G, Cadbury, GlaxoSmithKline, Unilever etc.
- Necruited erudite talent and structured a team of **over 35 people** viz. Corporate Sales Managers-Ad Sales, SME Sales Managers-Ad Sales, Tele Sales Managers & Executives, and Customer Support
- ♡ Tasked to handle the 3Mn USD P&L accountability.
- ♡ Created history by achieving the **break even** in the organization

Vishnu Vardhan | Linkedin- www.linkedin.com/in/vardhanvishnu | YouTube- http://tiny.cc/vishnuvardhan | www.vishnuvardhan.net

#### As Digital Sales Manager (Apr 11 - Sep 12)

- Significantly contributed in organizing Business Forums to Train SME's and developing BTL marketing strategy & business intelligence with an aim of attaining business goals & Objectives
- Solution Evolved Pre-sales material/ sales collaterals/Sales Presentation along with development of prospective advertisers' data in lead based and tenure based categories
- D Headed a team of over 20 Digital Sales Professionals and identified and developed new streams for revenue growth

Accolades Received: Outstanding Leadership Award – VConnect Global Service Limited

#### **Area Sales Manager** ▶ Multipro Enterprise Ltd.

Apr 2010 - Apr 2011

Multipro Enterprise Ltd, Lagos, part of Tolaram Corporation Pte Ltd, Singapore. The Company's Core business is selling and distribution of Indomie Instant Noodles in Africa. Indomie Instant Noodles is the World's largest selling instant noodles

- Played an imperative role in leading a team of 12 Sales Officers, engaged in Traditional Trade, Modern Trade and Small Town Distribution Development
- Managed the spectrum of selling activities of world's largest instant noodle brand "Indomie" and ace professional skills in FMCG Sales involving Dealers Management, Numeric Distribution and Category Penetration, etc.
- D Proved a resource to the organisation by:
  - Effectuating robust systems and training manpower for consistent deliveries of sales and distribution objectives
  - Building philosophy of re-distribution thereby reducing dependency on wholesale
  - Developing exclusivity concept to sub dealers
- Successfully appointed 5 new business partners in order to ensure the product reach in the market
- Strengthened business by rejuvenating territories to ensure growth in the all areas as well as managed local consumer activations & sampling, sales promotions and BTL marketing activities

## Marketing Executive – Strategy ► Kavi Imaging

(Jun 2007 - Mar 2008)

**Role in Brief**: Contributed in developing the marketing strategies & plan for this small town start-up in digital printing space within the company budgets

#### **Educational Brief**

MBA (Marketing) ► IBS Pune (ICFAI University) ► secured 8 CGPA

2010

**B.Tech.** (Information Technology) ▶ Tamilnadu College of Engineering (Anna University) ▶ secured 68%

2007

# **Other Credentials**:

- ☼ Dale Carnegie Certified Trainer
- ℧ TESOL Train the Trainer

#### **Summer Internship**

<u>Organization</u>: Business Development Bureau Limited, Pune || <u>Duration</u>: 3 Months <u>Title</u>: Potential of Pneumatics for Marine Business in India

# Accolades Earned "Award of Excellence" for Summer Internship Program from Business Development Bureau (India) Pvt. Ltd. "Award of Appreciation for Presentation skills" from Mr. Ashok Soota - Former Chairman - Mindtree Consulting Received Best Case Study Award from Mr. Nitin Paranjpe (CEO Hindustan Unilever Ltd.), titled "Pond's Tooth Paste - Importance of Brand Recognition" Presented Case study Analysis in "Vimarsh 08" in Kohinoor Business School

Position of Responsibility			
Elected as Student Chairman — Tamilnadu College of Engineering	<ul> <li>Represented 300 students of the department and communicate students' issues to the management followed by resolving their successfully</li> <li>Organized and led National Level Technical Symposiums "XPLOEZ" in 05' &amp; 06'</li> </ul>		
Elected as - Student Council Head - IBS	<ul> <li>Escalated several issues of the students to the management an resolved successfully as well</li> <li>Engaged in the selection of 5 members, who represented 286 business management students</li> </ul>		
Chief Organizer - Management Fest - IBS	<ul> <li>Organized National Level Management Fest "ZEAL 10" with participar strength of over 200 participants from various business schools</li> <li>Hosted National Level Management Quiz as "Quiz Master" in the ever</li> </ul>		

Vishnu Vardhan | Linkedin- www.linkedin.com/in/vardhanvishnu | YouTube- http://tiny.cc/vishnuvardhan | www.vishnuvardhan.net

	গ	Facilitated as:
Others		<ul> <li>Public Relation Officer of Marketing Club in IBS</li> </ul>
		<ul> <li>Placement cell representative in Tamilnadu College of</li> </ul>
		Engineering and IBS Pune
	5	Represented IBS in AIMA National Level Student Management Quiz

#### **Extra-Curricular Activities / Achievements**

- ♡ Presented Budget Analysis in "Yes Finance Minister 2009" annual event IBS Pune
- ♡ Finalist "Acumen" in Megabucks 09 IIT Kanpur
- ♡ Won First prize in intra college Creativity competition "Art Attack 08" in IBS Pune
- ♥ Won Best Actor Award for an English Skit at 'Utsav 08' event at IBS Pune
- Significant in "Debate competition" in Kohinoor Business School and "Debate" in "Amaze 08" in IIPM Pune
- S First Prize in intra-college debate competition for the annual event "Luminosita 06"

#### **Recommendations:**

# Dr. Dharmesh K Mishra, Professor at AMITY

Vishnu Vardhan is a highly passionate, energetic and positive individual. He takes up all tasks in a creative and innovative manner. He is a true team leader and a very charismatic individual. His drive and his passion always motivated his group to give the best in the class tasks at IBS. He is a good researcher, an excellent orator and a motivator. At IBS Vishnu was always the first choice in compering guest lectures and events such as the Annual Management Fest Zeal .The above skills enabled him to get an overseas job offer with the Tolaram Group where Vishnu has made his mark. With his positive attitude, perseverance and ability to lead and motivate a team, Vishnu will always be a key asset in the organization where he chooses to be.

#### Deepankar Rustagi, GM & Founder, VConnect.com.

Vishnu would be a greatest asset to any company. He is one of the brightest team members we ever had. I am impressed with his drive, determination, leadership and passion. He is highly ethical and an articulate speaker with excellent sales, marketing, team building and training skills alongside being a quick learner. He handled the entire revenue and he played a vital role in achieving the break-even first time in the history of VConnect. He is an excellent trainer and he had trained over 25,000 SME Entrepreneurs on digital marketing. Vishnu is nothing short of an empathetic leader and he will be an asset to any growing company.

#### Anand, CTO, VConnect.com.

Vishnu is one of the best people manager I have come across. He is full of ideas & great mass of energy, his way of working is supportive & creates conducive environment which motivates his Team Members to deliver. He has the gift of gab and he is definitely a crowd pleaser. Under his able leadership SME Vertical was able to set new milestones in customer acquisition. His idea of "Flash" a missed call based consumer engagement concept revolutionized the consumer marketing in a big way. A great team leader moreover a good human being. It was a great pleasure to work with him.